Tyrone Cloma

New York City, NY • 929-398-1598 • tyrone.cloma0219@gmail.com • GitHub • LinkedIn • Portfolio

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Developer with a passion for creating efficient and engaging applications. Experienced in JavaScript with React for creating responsive user interfaces, and Ruby on Rails for producing RESTful APIs. A self-starter that possesses strong skills in collaboration, resourcefulness, and an eagerness to learn that helps companies create innovative solutions for their clients.

PROJECTS

Hover Note / TypeScript & React / GitHub / Demo

A note-taking application that allows users to utilize Markdown syntax to create sticky notes

- Established a secure data flow between the local file system and the application using Electron.js' context bridge and IPC channels
- Leveraged React's useCallBack to memoize updates to the text editor and reliably handle a constant stream of input without affecting performance
- Utilized React Router loader functions to programmatically fetch data based on route parameters

Flypto Crypto / React & Ruby on Rails / GitHub / Demo

A web application that allows users to view and trade mock cryptocurrencies

- Visualized currency data acquired from the CoincapAPI along different time periods using Fusion Charts
- Simulated a complete trading experience through a RESTful API built in Ruby on Rails to handle user CRUD
 actions and authentication with sessions and cookies
- Created a cohesive design system for the React front-end using SASS and CSS Modules

Cosmo Quizzer / Next.js & Prisma / GitHub

A space-themed quiz game that tests your JavaScript and React knowledge

- Employed Next.js' getStaticProps function to do server-side data fetching and improve page load times by statically generating the website
- Persisted user scores using Prisma to create a RESTful API that links to a PostgreSQL database
- Leveraged the PixelEncounter API for reusable assets and styled them using TailwindCSS

EXPERIENCE

Sacred Goddess Studio, Brooklyn, NY

Web Developer

10/2022 - Present

- Developed a headless Shopify storefront using Next.js and TailwindCSS displaying content fetched from the Shopify Storefront GraphQL API
- Optimized the SEO of the webpage by proper use of Semantic HTML, attaching descriptive information in meta tags, and adding integrations for Open Graph
- Organized product database to a cohesive model, decreasing time spent looking for inventory prices and backlogs and optimizing semantic tags

Product Assistant 05/2021 - 06/2022

- Utilized Trello and Google Sheets to manage weekly workflow, which included taking product inventory, calculating prices, preparing for weekly sales, invoicing, and packaging
- Collaborated with the lead designer to create brand assets by utilizing Canva and Adobe Photoshop
- Formulated standard excel functions to create a cohesive pricing system for the inventory

Half Price Movers, Queens, NY

11/2022 - Present

Freelance Software Developer

- Developed an internal web application that streamlines the process of customer documentation, sales analytics, and price generation
- Worked remotely with an IT team for daily task assignments and work feedback

SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SASS, TailwindCSS, Java, Spring Boot, Python, Flask, Rust

Tools and Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Supabase, Git, GraphQL, Webpack, Bash

EDUCATION

Flatiron School , New York, NY Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript program	06/2022 - 10/2022
Ateneo de Manila University, Manila, Philippines Coursework completed toward a BS in Computer Science	04/2019 - 02/2021